It seems a paradox, does it not,
Parece una paradoja, ¿no es así,
the Retina should be inverted?
que la imagen formada en
la Retina debe ser invertida?
It is puzzling, why is it
we do not see things upside-down?
Es desconcertante, ¿por qué es
no vemos las cosas al revés?
You have never heard the Theory,
then, that the Brain also is inverted?
Nunca has oído la Teoría,
entonces, que el Cerebro también se invierte?
No indeed! What a beautiful fact!
¡No, en verdad! ¡Qué hermoso hecho!
But how is it proved?
Thus: what we call
Pero, ¿cómo se prueba?
Así: lo que llamamos
the vertex of the Brain
is really its base
el vértice del Cerebro
es realmente su base
and what we call its base
is really its vertex,
y lo que llamamos su base
es realmente su vértice
it is simply a question of nomenclature.
How truly delightful!
se trata simplemente de una cuestión de nomenclatura.
¡Qué delicia!